E: BatulMrakkan@gmail.com | T: +966 58 338 0165 | LinkedIn: Batul Mrakkan | GitHub: BatulMoneer

SUMMARY

A passionate **computer science graduate**, and a frontend developer, who enjoys coding and finding new ways to solve problems, enjoys designing and creating and optimizing user interfaces and user experience, always seeks knowledge and new experiences, loves arts, and has a creative artistic sense.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Soft Skills

- Creative Thinking
- Time Management
- Responsibility
- Flexibility
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Critical Thinking
- Logic

Applied Skills

- Working with Angular Framework
- Programming with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, and Python
- Familiar with React and FastAPI Frameworks
- UXUI Designing
- Troubleshooting and debugging
- Professional Artist (Fine Arts, Sculpting, Digital Arts)

EDUCATION -

Umm Al-Qura University (UQU)

Ranked by the Times Higher Education the 6th rank locally and 559th rank globally.

BSc in Computer Science Umm Al-Qura University, Makkah, SA

(Aug 2020 - Jun 2024)

- GPA: 4.00 out of 4.00.
- First Class Honor.
- Graduation Project: Nadeem | Educational Tales with Illustrations and Audio Using Deep Learning Algorithm with "A+ Grade".

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• FirstCity Front-End Internship Intern

(Jun 2024 – Aug 2024)

An internship program supported by FirstCity Company, that aims to teach the trainees different important aspects of labor market, and the program was split into two sections, frontend development and backend development.

Worked as a frontend angular developer in a team of 4 to develop an integrated website called <u>Sahel.</u> Gained and Applied Skills:

• Scrum Agile Project Management • Project Structure • Components and Modules • Services and Routing • Forms and Validation • HTTP and Data Retrieval

• AwonTech UXUI Internship Intern

(Jul 2023 – Aug 2023)

An internship program supported by AwonTech Charity, the program focused on teaching the trainees how to work as a team, and the program consisted of three aspects, UXUI development, SRS file Writing, and Website Testing.

Worked as a UXUI designer in a team of 5 to restructure and redesign the interfaces of Vibrant Community - Mawarid Gained and Applied Skills:

•Interfaces Design using Figma •SRS file writing •Website Testing

• Tuting and Assistance tutor

(Jan 2019 – May 2021)

Worked as a tutor for different academic levels, and different materials and subjects, where some of these tutorials were paid and others were voluntary.

Helped students and gave as much knowledge as I can

Gained and Applied Skills:

Teaching •Communication •Learn and Educate More •Work with and helped different personalities

• Professional Artist, Art Commissions freelancer

(Jan 2018 - Present)

Make Art pieces with different art fields, whether they were digital or on paper, portraits or landscapes, managed on a business Instagram account.

Successfully completed more than 50 art commissions over the last 5 years.

Gained and Applied Skills:

•Independency •Improve Art

Projects ——

• Sahel, FirstCity Internship

(Jun 2024 - Aug 2024)

A website that combines different big stores in one place, developed using Angular, and connected to the backend using APIs.

• Nadeem, Graduation Project

(Nov 2023 – Jun 2024)

A website integrated with AI to generate stories based on child preferences enriched with images and a reading voice, using React and FastAPI

Gained and Applied Skills:

• Finetuning Stable Diffusion Models with three techniques • Integrating OpenAI voice and text APIs • Using FastAPI for the APIs • Using React to implement the interfaces

• Vibrant Community Mawarid, AwonTech Internship

(Jul 2023 – Aug 2023)

Restructuring and designing Vibrant Community's Mawarid's interfaces using Figma.

AWARDS AND HONORS —

• Dean's List of Honor, Academic Excellence

(Jun 2024)

• She Codes 2024 Best Graduation Project 1st Place

(May 2024)

• General Administration of Education in Makkah, REFQ Forum 1st Place

(Aug 2016)

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES -

• Google Developer Student Club | UQU Member of Member Affairs Committee

(Aug 2023 – Jun 2024)

Contributed to organizing and completing any assigned tasks to me

• Rouh Volunteer Team Member

(Jan 2018 – Oct 2019)

A team that makes charitable works and initiatives to help people in need

LANGUAGES -

- Arabic
- English